Inventory of the William Parmer Fuller Papers, 1920-1962
Hoover Institution Archives
William Parmer Fuller Papers,
1920-1962
57007
Fuller, William Parmer, 1888-1969
3 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 3 album boxes, 5 envelopes, 1 phonotape reel (4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, clippings, telegrams, photographs, and memorabilia, relating to American Relief Administration work in Poland at the end of World War I, and to Herbert Hoover. Includes correspondence with Herbert and Lou Henry Hoover.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
American Relief Administration.; American Relief Administration. European Children's Fund.; International relief.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; Poland.; United States--Foreign relations.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hoover, Lou Henry, 1874-1944.
Container List
- Correspondence and telegrams exchanged between Herbert and Lou Henry Hoover and Adaline and W. Parmer Fuller, 1920-1962 (Box 1: 1)
- W. P. Fuller's diary pertaining to his activities in the Mission to Poland of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund, 1919-1921 (Box 1: 2)
- Correspondence, reports, memoranda, telegrams, etc., pertaining to W. P. Fuller's activities in the Mission to Poland of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund, 1919 (Box 1: 3-5)
- Correspondence, reports, memoranda, telegrams, etc., pertaining to W. P. Fuller's activities in the Mission to Poland of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund, 1920 (Box 1: 6-7)
- Correspondence, reports, memoranda, telegrams, etc., pertaining to W. P. Fuller's activities in the Mission to Poland of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund, 1920-1921 (Box 1: 8-9)
- Correspondence, reports, memoranda, telegrams, etc., pertaining to W. P. Fuller's activities in the Mission to Poland of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund, 1920-1922 (Box 2: 1-3)
- Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 2: 4)
- United States. Department of State. Correspondence, reports, memoranda, etc., regarding property rights of United States citizens in Mexico, 1927 (Box 2: 5)
- Case histories of Polish families aided by the Mission to Poland of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund (Box 3: 1)
- Maps of Polish-speaking and surrounding areas during World War I (Box 3: 2)
- Miscellaneous reports, clippings, personal notes, and memorabilia. (Box 3: 3)
- Notes on Trip with Hoover Mission, March-June, 1946 (Box 3: 4)
- Medals. Includes Hoover medal from Argentina, 1928 December 13; Edith Cavell medal, 1915; Medal commemorating the "Bataille de la Marne," dated September 1914 (Box 3: 5)
- Miscellany (Box 3: 6)
- American Relief Administration European Children's fund estimated cost of operations book, 1920 (Box 4: 1)
- One album of watercolor hand-painted thank-yous to W. P. Fuller and Polish posters (Box fF-fI)
- One flattened scroll containing a handwritten thank-you to W. P. Fuller (Box fF-fI)
- Albums and Photographs, 333 prints / 174 negatives / 5 envelopes / 3 oversize boxes (Box 57007 - 10.A-V, 57007 - 8M.02)
  - 2 prints of Mrs. W. Parmer Fuller and others; 1 print of Mr. and Mrs. W. Parmer Fuller and others; 1 print of Herbert C. Hoover and others of the Supreme Economic Counsel, Paris Peace Conference, Paris, 1919; 11 prints of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund activities in Poland, 1919-1920. (Folder mA)
  - 83 prints of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund activities in Poland and Czechoslovakia, 1919-1920 (Folder B)
  - 44 prints of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund activities in Poland., 1919-1920 (Folder C)
  - 91 prints of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund activities in Poland., 1919-1920 (Folder D)
  - 1 print of W. Parmer Fuller; 61 prints of American Relief Administration European Children's Fund activities in Romania; 8 prints of American Relief Administration European Children's Fund activities in Poland; 41 prints of Queen Marie of Romania and others; 34 postcards of European scenes., undated (Folder E)
  - 36 oversize pages of mounted photographs of scenes in Poland., 1919-1920 (Folder 4: fF)
  - 1 photograph album of schools, orphanages, and scenes in Poland., 1919-1920. (Folder 4: fG)
  - 1 photograph album of schools, orphanages, and scenes in Poland., 1919-1920 (Folder 4: fH)
  - 1 photograph album of Lithuanian schools, orphanages, and scenes., 1919-1920 (Folder 4: fI)
  - 1 photograph album of American Relief Administration European Children's Fund personnel and activities in Poland., 1919-1920 (Folder 5: fJ)
  - 1 photograph album of American Relief Administration European Children's Fund personnel and activities in Poland., 1919-1920 (Folder 5: fK)
  - 1 photograph album of American Relief Administration European Children's Fund personnel and activities in Poland., 1919-1920 (Folder fL)
  - 174 negatives, undated (Folder fM)